Contact

sahilsharma2107@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sahil-sharma-13540375 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Leadership
Public Speaking
Management

Certifications

Python for Data Science & Machine Learning

Financial Modelling

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Python Data Structures

Linear Classifiers in Python

Sahil Sharma

Building Gen Al Products | ML Engineering | Senior Data Scientist at Singapore Airlines Ltd | NUS

Singapore

Summary

As a Senior Data Scientist at Singapore Airlines, I apply the latest advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) to digitize operations and enhance decision-making processes. I work on building generative AI applications, fine-tuning language and logic models (LLMs) for aviation, and developing LLM plugins platforms for various use cases. I use deep neural networks, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Langchain, AWS, and SQL as my core tools and technologies.

Previously, I was a Data Science Intern at Munich Re, where I experimented with free medical text to increase the accuracy of the existing ML models. I solved ICD-10 code classification on free medical text using natural language processing (NLP), deep learning, and transformer models, achieving an overall F1 score of 84% on unseen data in multiple languages. I also reproduced, tested, and enhanced algorithms from research papers to improve the NLP performance.

I hold a Master of Science in Data Science & Analytics from National University of Singapore, where I also worked as an AI Researcher in the Department of Analytics and Operations. In addition to this, I've 4 years of experience as a Management Consultant and have also completed multiple certifications in financial modeling, Python, and Hadoop. I am passionate about unlocking valuable insights and transforming the way businesses operate with AI/ML. I am always eager to learn new skills, collaborate with diverse teams, and explore new challenges and opportunities in the AI/ML domain.

Experience

Singapore Airlines Senior Data Scientist November 2022 - Present (11 months) Singapore, Singapore

Secondment to SIAEC

Skills: Generative AI app development, aviation LLM fine-tuning, LLM plugins platform development, Deep Neural Networks, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Langchain, AWS and SQL

Building Recommender systems, QA engines, chatbots to streamline flight safety and maintenance, finance, and customer feedback

Munich Re

Data Science Intern (Life & Health)
May 2022 - September 2022 (5 months)

Singapore, Singapore

Skills: Deep Neural Networks, Pytorch, Tensorflow, fine-tune LLMs

Capstone Project through National University of Singapore (Mentor: Prof. James Pang)- In this role, I experimented with free medical text such as doctor diagnoses and medical prescriptions to increase the accuracy of the existing Machine Learning models at Munich Re. I have solved ICD-10 code classification on free medical text using NLP techniques, Deep Learning, and Transformer models. Experimenting through different supervised and unsupervised techniques, the model gets an overall f1 score of 84% on unseen data including clinical text in multiple languages. I'm reproducing, testing, and enhancing algorithms from research papers to better the results.

X0PA AI

NLP Engineer intern November 2021 - April 2022 (6 months)

Singapore, Singapore

Used Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning to prototype 'X0PA Al Room', a video interview platform that rates candidates using scoring metrics based on text transcripts, topic modeling, sentiments, and confidence. The idea behind the product is to remove manual evaluation of candidates by enabling Al based scoring. To build this product, I worked extensively to develop pipelines from various data sources and extract features from them.

National University of Singapore
Al Researcher (Department of Analytics and Operations)
September 2021 - November 2021 (3 months)
Singapore, Singapore

NUS Business Analytics Centre: Academic research on Incentive Mechanism for Federated Learning and DeepChain in the research group groomed by Prof. James Pang and Prof. Khor Ping. Applied machine learning algorithms with homomorphic encryption to maintain data privacy while model training.

EY

Business Consultant January 2019 - July 2021 (2 years 7 months) India, Kuwait, KSA and Egypt

I've assisted Boards and Executives in defining ICT strategies, ICT Vision and Mission statements, managing and assessing technology solutions to address business challenges and risks.

I've managed teams and executed technology implementations and assessments such as ERP, BI, digitization, analytics, and cloud across FS and TMT industries. I've participated in public speaking events within the Gulf region and have contributed to white papers on telecom sector disruption and cloud adoption.

KPMG India Associate Consultant September 2017 - January 2019 (1 year 5 months) India

As an Associate in the Urban Transformation practice in the Business Advisory vertical, I've worked on strategy & implementation projects in the Public Sector, helping International Donor Agencies, Central and State Governments with investment planning by building sustainable financial models and presenting future-oriented frameworks.

PayU

Software Engineer, Analytics August 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 2 months) India

Member of the analytics team which leveraged data to help PayU (Naspers Group) grow its business through a wide range of products.

Tech stack: HIVE, Python, SQL, and Tableau.

KPMG India
Technology Consulting Analyst
May 2015 - September 2015 (5 months)
Page 3 of 4

Gurugram, Haryana, India

Ambit International
Market Research Analyst
August 2014 - November 2014 (4 months)
Chandigarh, India

Lead a team of 15 interns to enhance the livelihood of street vendors in Tricity (Chandigarh, Panchkula and Mohali) and ideate branding opportunities for them.

Education

National University of Singapore Master of Science, Data Science & Analytics

PEC University of Technology, Chandigarh Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science